那么模型的简介咱们就先说到这里
So let’s start with the introduction of the model here.
现在呢我们来尝试一下
Now let's try it
他们在同样的编程任务上的表现
How well they performed on the same programming tasks
究竟如何
exactly how
我们现在先来到控制台
Let's go to the console now
在Claude这一侧
On Claude's side
如果我们要更新
If we want to update
具体的说
Specifically
如果我们使用的是Claude Code
If we are using Claude Code
要更新这个命令行工具呢
Do I need to update this command line tool?
就用claude update
Just use claude update
当前最新的版本就是2.1.32
The latest version is 2.1.32
对于Codex命令行
For Codex command line
我们要做的呢
What are we going to do?
就是通过npm install来更新
Just update through npm install
升级到最新版本以后
After upgrading to the latest version
我们现在用claude
We now use claude
打开后默认的就已经切到了Opus 4.6
After opening it, Opus 4.6 has been switched to Opus 4.6 by default.
我们通过/model这个命令
We pass the /model command
能查看目前的模型情况
Can view the current model status
默认呢就是Opus 4.6
The default is Opus 4.6
在右侧Codex同样启动它
Start it on the right side of Codex as well
同样的使用model命令
Use the model command similarly
来看看GPT-5.3-Codex
Let’s take a look at GPT-5.3-Codex
已经可以使用
Already available
我们可以将它切换过来
We can switch it over
推理的能力或程度呢
What about the ability or degree of reasoning?
默认是medium
The default is medium
它兼具了速度和推理的深度
It combines speed with depth of reasoning
根据自己的偏好来吧
Come according to your preference
我就保持默认使用medium好了
I'll just keep using medium as the default.
这两个命令行工具都已经准备就绪
Both command line tools are ready
那接下来要做什么呢
So what's next?
我先通过Claude Code
I first pass Claude Code
把现在这个应用程序呢运行起来
Run the current application
这是一个我模仿Typeless编写的
This is a code I wrote in imitation of Typeless
实际上是vibe coding做的
It was actually made by vibe coding
一个语音输入的小工具
A voice input gadget
我期望尝试一下
I hope to try it
看看这种语音输入的程序
Check out this voice input program
究竟是怎么写的
How is it written?
我先简单做一番介绍吧
Let me give you a brief introduction first.
将它启动
start it
在这个系统的托盘里
in the system tray
会有一个弹出菜单
There will be a pop-up menu
可以对希望使用的模型做配置
You can configure the model you want to use
今天的重点呢
What's the focus of today?
是来看两款模型的编程能力
Let’s look at the programming capabilities of the two models.
这款小工具并不是今天的主要话题
This gadget is not the main topic today
我们就不过多的讨论了
We won’t discuss too much
我要交给他的任务是什么呢
What is the task I want to give him?
我是期望他能够集成
I hope he can integrate
新的一个语音转文字的模型接口
A new speech-to-text model interface
Mistral发布了新模型Voxtral Mini Transcribe 2
Mistral releases new model Voxtral Mini Transcribe 2
这正好是这两天新发布的模型
This happens to be the newly released model in the past two days
我希望将其集成到这款小的工具里
I hope to integrate it into this little tool
这样就多了一个语音识别的选项
This gives you one more voice recognition option
语音模型的使用在这里呢
The use of speech models is here
有专门的文档介绍
There is a dedicated document introduction
我会将文档交给Claude Code以及Codex
I will give the documentation to Claude Code and Codex
分别让它们完成这个任务的执行
Let them complete the execution of this task respectively.
实现这部分功能
Implement this part of the function
我们来看看它的处理效果有什么区别
Let’s take a look at the difference in its processing effects
在Codex这里
Here at Codex
我首先呢
Me first
期望它用git来创建一个worktree
Expect it to use git to create a worktree
这样使得我们的开发工作能够并行
This allows our development work to be parallelized
两个AI工具
Two AI tools
分别在自己不同的工作区
In their own different workspaces
进行编程工作
Do programming work
Codex帮我创建了这么一个新的工作区
Codex helped me create such a new workspace
我们现在
we now
开始工作
start working
我已经把文档的链接
I have put the link to the documentation
以及要使用的模型ID
and the model ID to use
交给了这两个AI工具
handed over to these two AI tools
接下来就通过语音输入的方式
Next, use voice input
给到他们我的需求吧
Give them what I need
现在
Now
我已经给了你要集成的模型的文档
I've given you the documentation for the model you want to integrate
以及我希望使用的模型的ID
and the ID of the model I wish to use
你需要来理解如何使用Mistral的API
You need to understand how to use Mistral's API
如何使用这个新模型
How to use this new model
帮助我将它集成到目前
Help me integrate it into the current
这个语音输入的项目中
In this voice input project
代码修改完成以后
After the code modification is completed
不要运行程序
Don't run the program
我会在测试的时候再来运行
I'll run it again during testing
现在的输入呢
What is the current input?
就是通过这个语音输入的工具完成的
It’s done through this voice input tool.
实际上这里还是有一点小误差
In fact, there is still a small error here
它不是Metro是Mistral
It's not Metro, it's Mistral
将这段文字复制
Copy this text
同样给到Claude Code
Also given to Claude Code
我们尝试一下吧
let's try it
让它同时执行任务
Let it perform tasks simultaneously
看看两边的执行进度怎么样
Let’s take a look at the execution progress on both sides.
现在呢任务执行完毕
Now the task is completed
从Claude Code这边来看
From the perspective of Claude Code
它花了2分13秒
it took 2 minutes and 13 seconds
在Codex命令行这里
Here in the Codex command line
我发现它对每一次任务执行
I found that it executes for every task
似乎并没有一个计时的一个功能
There doesn’t seem to be a timing function
所以我并不知道它花了多久
So I don't know how long it took
我提了问
I asked a question
你花了多长时间完成这个任务
How long did it take you to complete this task
他说大约12分钟
He said about 12 minutes
实际上呢
Actually
我观测了他们的时间
I observed their time
几乎一致
almost unanimous
没有太大差别
not much difference
当然了这只是一个具体的开发任务
Of course, this is just a specific development task
我们不能简单的通过这个任务的执行
We cannot simply pass the execution of this task
来评判这两款模型在开发工作中
To judge the development work of these two models
整体的开发速度
overall development speed
开发效率
Development efficiency
不过可以给大家一个参考吧
But I can give you a reference.
更重要的是
What's more important
我们来看看它的开发质量究竟怎么样
Let’s take a look at its development quality
两边在任务执行后
After the task is executed, both sides
其实都给到了一个总结
In fact, a summary was given
他们调了什么样的接口
What kind of interface did they adjust?
用了什么样的参数
What parameters were used?
支持了什么样的模型
What models are supported?
我们可以看到都用到了POST
We can see that POST is used
然后用的是这个Audio Transcription这个API
Then I use the Audio Transcription API
模型来讲
In terms of models
扩展了两个模型
Two models were extended
在这里它有提到
Here it is mentioned
Voxtral Mini 2602是默认的
Voxtral Mini 2602 is the default
另外
in addition
它还支持到了latest这个标签的模型
It also supports the model with the latest tag
这个和Claude Code非常一致
This is very consistent with Claude Code
都是同样的两款模型的支持
Both models are supported by the same
接下来
Next
我们要做的就是运行程序来测试
All we have to do is run the program to test
先让Claude Code来做吧
Let Claude Code do it first
程序已经打包启动
The program has been packaged and started
我们现在要做的
what we have to do now
首先来到Settings
First come to Settings
看看是否有新的选项
See if there are any new options
在Transcription这里确实有Mistral
There is indeed Mistral here in Transcription
好了现在呢
Okay now
我配置一个Mistral API key
I configure a Mistral API key
来测试一下端到端的情况吧
Let’s test the end-to-end situation
看看是否能够正常的进行语音转文字
See if you can convert speech to text normally
我已经完成了API key的配置
I have completed the configuration of API key
那接下来是不是就可以开始测试了呢
Then can we start testing next?
这就是刚才语音输入以后
This is what happened after the voice input just now
帮我填写到Claude Code的文字
Help me fill in the text to Claude Code
大家觉得效果怎么样呢
What do you think of the effect?
至少在目前这个版本的测试上
At least in the current version of testing
我觉得他工作一切正常
I think he's working fine
那现在我们回到Codex
Now let’s go back to Codex
在这个worktree里面重新的打包
Repackage it in this worktree
我们来测试一下他开发的这个版本
Let's test this version he developed
好了花了一些时间
Okay, it took some time
Codex才将这个应用程序启动起来
Codex just launched this application
对比于Claude Code
Compared to Claude Code
似乎他对Swift这套开发环境呢
It seems that he is interested in the Swift development environment.
并不是太熟悉
Not too familiar
当然了这只是我个人的一些感觉
Of course, these are just my personal feelings.
确实Codex花的时间会长一些
It is true that Codex will take longer.
不过它现在也启动了
But it's also started now
我们来看一下设置部分
Let’s take a look at the settings part
同样我们来配置一下API key
Similarly, let’s configure the API key
除此以外
Apart from this
咱们还需要配一个OpenAI的API key
We also need to configure an OpenAI API key
那接下来是不是就可以开始测试了呢
Then can we start testing next?
我已经完成了key的配置
I have completed the key configuration
那接下来是不是就可以开始测试了呢
Then can we start testing next?
看起来还是不错
Still looks good
虽然key这个识别略有瑕疵
Although the identification of key is slightly flawed,
也有可能是我的发音不够清晰
It's also possible that my pronunciation is not clear enough
那整体来讲
So overall
端到端的功能
End-to-end functionality
两个模型都能够很好的完成
Both models can be completed well
这个需求
This demand
其实还是一个比较简单的需求
In fact, it is a relatively simple requirement
有明确的文档
Have clear documentation
有明确的需求
Have clear needs
因此我觉得这两款模型在执行上
Therefore, I think these two models are better in execution
都非常的顺利
Everything went very smoothly